<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>infographic on Sofia Foladori Invernizzi</title>
    <link>https://sofiafoladori.github.io/tags/infographic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in infographic on Sofia Foladori Invernizzi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sofiafoladori.github.io/tags/infographic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>The menstrual cycle</title>
      <link>https://sofiafoladori.github.io/posts/menstrual-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sofiafoladori.github.io/posts/menstrual-cycle/</guid>
      <description>Understanding the menstrual cycle is fundamental in comprehending changes in hormones, the menstrual phase, and the ovulation and fertile period. In addition, it is important to understand the differences between the uterus and the ovaries, and what function each has.
Objective Organize the information about the menstrual cycle regarding the uterus and ovary phase
Workflow The information regarding the menstrual cycle was systemized in PowerPoint to produce a simple infographic</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding COVID-19 in Brazil</title>
      <link>https://sofiafoladori.github.io/posts/covid-infographic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sofiafoladori.github.io/posts/covid-infographic/</guid>
      <description>The COVID-19 pandemic has reached all portions of the world, and countries have taken different measures to respond to the threat presented by the virus. The propagation of the virus is related to several issues, including population density, measures taken, number of doctors, and ICU beds.
Objective This project tried to visualize the COVID-19 cases in Brazil. Specifically, it compared the distribution of COVID-19 cases and mortality, the population density, the number of doctors and ICU beds in the public health care system (SUS), and the restriction measurements taken at the beginning of the pandemic in each state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microfibers in clothes</title>
      <link>https://sofiafoladori.github.io/posts/microfibers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sofiafoladori.github.io/posts/microfibers/</guid>
      <description>Clothes production is big, and the use of synthetic fibers like polyester, acrylic, spandex, and nylon is increasing. These fibers, specifically small pieces in microscale eg. Microfibers, can be released during washing cycles. This process allows the fibers to be transported into oceans, rivers, and lakes, as they cannot be easily filtered. Once in the water, they enter the food chain and consequently come into our plates when we consume fish and seafood.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
