<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GIS on Data Science Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://hugo-toha.github.io/tags/gis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GIS on Data Science Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo-toha.github.io/tags/gis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>How are the science and technology journals authorships distributed?</title>
      <link>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/science-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/science-technology/</guid>
      <description>Scientific publications are concentrated in developed countries, that have the economic power, the most prestigious universities, and the most diffused scientific journals. The investigation agendas are set up by the central countries, such as the United States and some European countries. Consequently, once these countries define the research topics, these are adopted by satellite groups. In this context, we find Latin America and their academic production
Objective If we consider the most prestigious journals in Science and technology, from which country are the authors?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding COVID-19 in Brazil</title>
      <link>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/covid-infographic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/covid-infographic/</guid>
      <description>The COVID-19 pandemic has reached all portions of the world, and countries have taken different measures to respond to the threat presented by the virus. The propagation of the virus is related to several issues, including population density, measures taken, number of doctors, and ICU beds.
Objective This project tried to visualize the COVID-19 cases in Brazil. Specifically, it compared the distribution of COVID-19 cases and mortality, the population density, the number of doctors and ICU beds in the public health care system (SUS), and the restriction measurements taken at the beginning of the pandemic in each state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flooded Area of Brumadinho (Brazil)</title>
      <link>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/brumadinho/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/brumadinho/</guid>
      <description>A map was done to compare the original flooded area of Brumadinho (Brazil) in 2018 due to the dam and the increase in the flooded extension after the breakage of the barrier in 2019, creating a giant environmental impact.
Workflow Output References ArcGIS
USGS satalite images
Landsat 8 (from 09.12.2018 and 04.22.2019)
Open Street Map</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
