<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Sofia Foladori Invernizzi</title>
    <link>https://sofiafoladori.github.io/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Sofia Foladori Invernizzi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sofiafoladori.github.io/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Bioinformatic analysis of the wheat rhizosphere microbiome</title>
      <link>https://sofiafoladori.github.io/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sofiafoladori.github.io/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>The health status of the soil is greatly dependent on the microorganism biodiversity due to the several ecosystem functions and soil processes they participate in. The interaction between soil microorganisms and roots is characterized as rhizosphere. Several factors affect the rhizosphere, but even with microbial community change the functions and processes may be maintained due to functional redundancy. Functional traits are morpho-physiophenological characteristics that indirectly impact fitness and a trait-based approach may facilitate predictions regarding the implications of the ecosystem and microbial processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 pandemic in Brazil Regression and PCA</title>
      <link>https://sofiafoladori.github.io/posts/covid-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sofiafoladori.github.io/posts/covid-regression/</guid>
      <description>This project seeks to understand the COVID-19 pandemic in Brazil. For this, we will do a regression analysis and a PCA to understand the impact of socioeconomic factors on the mortality due to SARS-CoV-2 in the different Brazilian states.
Objective Understand the relationship between socioeconomic factors and mortality caused by the virus SARS-CoV-2 Define which variables have a bigger impact on mortality Highlight important aspects where public policy should focus Cluster and PCA analysis that shows the different variables and the differences between the Brazilian states Linear regression and obtaining the significant variables in explaining mortality Workflow Data Socioeconomic data - obtained from IBGE IDHM data - obtained from PNUD Brazil COVID-19 deaths from the begging of the pandemic in Brazil until the 31/Dec/2020 - obtained from the national website https://covid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific production on the democratization of science a comparison between Web of Science and SciELO</title>
      <link>https://sofiafoladori.github.io/posts/democratization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sofiafoladori.github.io/posts/democratization/</guid>
      <description>Scientific publications on the subject of “democratization of science” were examined, showing the temporal and thematic patterns in two databases. Scientific publications, in all areas of knowledge, are concentrated in developed countries, which also hold economic power, the most prestigious universities, and the most widely distributed scientific journals. That translates to databases as well. In this project, we examine the Web of Science database, international and mostly in English, and SciELO, an Ibero-American database, where publications in Spanish and Portuguese are mainly concentrated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How are the science and technology journals authorships distributed?</title>
      <link>https://sofiafoladori.github.io/posts/science-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sofiafoladori.github.io/posts/science-technology/</guid>
      <description>Scientific publications are concentrated in developed countries, that have the economic power, the most prestigious universities, and the most diffused scientific journals. The investigation agendas are set up by the central countries, such as the United States and some European countries. Consequently, once these countries define the research topics, these are adopted by satellite groups. In this context, we find Latin America and their academic production
Objective If we consider the most prestigious journals in Science and technology, from which country are the authors?</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
